NIRVAN BAJRACHARYA

ABOUT ME

I am a recent graduate of University of West London, Ras Al Khaima with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science. Specializing in Front-end Development, keen on transitioning into Full-Stack Development and Software Development. Additionally, I possess a creative flair, excelling in Illustrations and UI/UX design.

EDUCATION

University of West London, Ras Al Khaimah, UAE

October 2020 - June 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Honours)

Overall classification of qualification: First Class Honors (Overall Average: 80%)

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Databases and Analytics, Applied Software Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

MindChamps Sept 2020 - Sept 2021

Illustrator and Web Designer (Internship)

- · Tasked to make illustrations for their blog posts
- · Created pages of their website
- · Designed their current logo

TCR Innovation Sept 2022 - Nov 2022

Data Analyst Intern

- · Learned Data processing methods in Python
- To train Machine Learning models

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming: C++ | Java | HTML/CSS | JavaScript | Python

Frameworks: React | Next.js | NodeJS | Flask | Tkinter | Pygame | Tailwaind | JQuery | OpenCV

Databases: Oracle/SQL | MongoDB

Data Analytics: Excel | Microsoft PowerBI | Jupyter Notebook | Pandas | Numpy | Matplotlib

Others: Illustrator | Photoshop | Blender | GIT | Wordpress | Figma | BurpSuite

PROJECTS

Form Manager Site

Flask, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery

- · Used JQuery to drag and save positions of forms for priority management
- · Allows CRUD functionality for forms in a user-friendly layout
- · Integrated the site with REST API architecture and stored data in a local database

Al Art Canvas (ML Application)

Python, Tkinter, OpenCV

- · Generates images from semantic input giving control of how image should generate
- Style transfer feature added where images can merge with art styles
- · Implemented the app with SPADE ML model to generate images
- · Designed the GUI of the app from using python library called Tkinter

ADDITIONAL INFOROMATION

Interests:

- Art 1st place in Interweave Art Competition 2016
- Graphic Design or UI/UX Design 2nd place in Design o Mania

Nationality: Nepalese